

lcarolinar@yahoo.com www.carolinaramirezconsulting.com www.linkedin.com/in/carolinaramirezconsulting +469-688-6824

ABOUT ME

Data driven web design and digital marketing professional with 10+ years of experience designing corporate websites and promoting brands. Proficient in front-end development, data analysis, graphic design, digital marketing (search engine optimization, pay per click) and analytical skills, high ability to find realistic e-solutions such as re-engineering web components to be more user-friendly and customized, design and implement applications for a very high traffic and large-scale websites.



WORK EXPERIENCE

THE TIME GROUP

Consultant - Digital Marketing, 2014 - now

Provide end-to-end web design and development services, delivering effective web presences, both static and content management-based websites, for small businesses, positively impacting their bottom line, Improve search engine visibility via search engine optimization practices Design.

Implement e-mail campaigns to meet email marketing objectives

Track usage, trends and conversions via web analytics

Manage social media marketing activities to produce leads and brand awarenes.

NATIONAL SOCIETY OF HISPANIC MBAS

Digital Media Specialist, 2010-2014

Rebranding of NSHMBA.org; textual content using HTML5 and CSS Interfaced with Blackbaud content management system to display standards-based content

Social Media Marketing

Design and Implement Email Campaigns

GREATER DALLAS HISPANIC CHAMBER OF COMMERCE

Frontend Development & Design, 2008-2010

Perform user experience research, develop information architectures and create web page wireframes

Design and Implement Email Campaigns to engage membership and events

HISPANIC YELLOW PAGES - DIRECTORIO EN ESPANOL

Seniour Communications Manager, 2003-2008

Proven ability to serve as the sole trainer on key customer accounts, to act as the senior trainer supporting new trainees, to conduct Train-the Trainer courses, and to provide product sales training for internal salespeople and internal staff. Provided solutions to multiple technical and business issues with organization-wide impact.

HISPANIC YELLOW PAGES

Software Developer Manager, 2002-2003

Develop and Design the new directory publishing software from lead generation to billing and collections.



TALENTS

User experience methodologies Responsive web design and hand coding Landing page design Email marketing campaigns Search engine optimization (SEO) Search engine marketing Social media marketing Web Analytics Content management systems (CMS)



PERSONAL SKILLS

Social Commitment	•	•	•	()	•
Organization	•	•	()	•	•
Creativity	•	•	•	•	•
Communication		•	•	O	()
Teamwork	•	•	•	•	•



LANGUAGES

English	•	•	•	•	0
Spanish		()	•	•	•



EDUCATION

IT & Software Developer

Cali, Colombia, 1994-1999 Universidad Autonoma



CERTIFICATIONS

WEB DEVELOPER

Dallas, Texas, 2003 Brookhaven College

DIGITAL MARKETING

Dallas, Texas, 2015 Interactive Advertising Bureau and Google

WEB ANALYTICS

Dallas, Texas, 2015 EOI Business School and Google



INTERNATIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Cooperativa de Transportadores de Risaralda

Software Developer, 2000 - 2002

straightforward developer role with emphasis on documentation, testing and complex change control for a transportation company improving delivery times process.

PERIODICO LA TARDE

Analyst and Reporting Specialist, 2000-1999

Design and execute automated procedures interfacing with systems to report business analytics and sales support indicators. Enquire from management, sales, departments and affiliates on data systems and reports.

CASA EDITORIAL EL TIEMPO

Analyst Specialist, 1999-1995

Collect, review and log data totals into database for reporting and ensure accuracy and report deliverables timelines. Oversee reports and deliverables complying with administrative invoicing.



SUMMARY

User experience specialist

2 years leveraging user experience methodologies, including user research and user testing

2 years creating user experience deliverables, including

Web designer and developer

7 years visual web design and hand coding HTML / XHTML

5 years hand coding CSS and creating visual designs in Photoshop

5 years working with content management systems

4 years styling ASP.NET & JSP applications with HTML / CSS

1 year experience with Adobe Flash & Illustrator

1 year fundamental experience with JavaScript and thejQuery library information architecture, wireframes

Internet marketing specialist

6 years search engine optimization within a web site design work-flow

4 years creating HTML email campaigns

3 years analyzing web analytics reports to track results, opportunities and performing A/B split testing to improve expected results

2 years social media marketing

TOOLS

Contact

lcarolinar@yahoo.com

+469-688-6824

www.carolinaramirezconsulting.com www.linkedin.com/in/carolinaramirezconsulting

Adobe Photoshop	•	•	•	•	•
Adobe Illustrator	()	•	•	•	•
Adobe InDesign	()	•	•	•	•
Adobe Dreamweaver	()	•	•	•	•
Blackbaud .net Community	()	•	•	•	•
Blackbaud Sphere	()	•	•	•	•
Constant Contact	()	•	•	•	0
Mailchimp	()	•	•	•	•
Campaigner	()	•	•	()	•
Google Analytics	()	•	•	O	•
Google Adwords	•	•	•	•	•



TECHNOLOGIES

HTML / HTML5 / XHTML	•	•	•	•	•
CSS / CSS3	•	•	•	•	•
JavaScript / jQuery	O	•	•	•	•